N. Suresh

AL - 202, Door No: F4, Santosh Apartment, 14th Main Road,

Anna Nagar, Chennai - 600040

Email: sureshn2585@gmail.com

Mob: +91-8248326358

PERSONAL SUMMARY

A well presented, industrious and highly personable individual who has extensive in-depth experience of the entire banking industry. Possessing a huge range of abilities from providing support and leadership to junior staff right through to being able to successfully sell the money, credit and products of a bank. Able to gain the trust of customers by interacting with people from all backgrounds. Also having a proven record of contributing to the profitability of previous employers by generating income and revenue growth. And looking forward to a making a significant contribution to a financial institution that offers a genuine opportunity for progression.

CAREER HISTORY

HDFC Bank Ltd

Manager E3 Band - Preferred Banking HNW

Sep 2013 - Jan 2017

Axis Bank Ltd

Assistant Manager - Wealth Manager

July 2012 - Sep 2013

Religare Securities Ltd

Deputy Manager

January 2010 - June 2012

Kotak Mahindra Bank Ltd, Chennai

Relationship Officer - Deputy Manager M2 Band

November 2006 - December 2009

Duties:

- Ensuring the smooth running of basic banking transactions.
- looking after the short term and long term funding requirements of business clients and individual customers.
- Advising clients on mortgages and raising loans.
- Building relationships with high net worth individuals.
- Answering any financial and banking queries.
- Providing advice on investments.
- Maintaining a professional image at all times.
- Putting into effect new procedures and policies passed down from Head Office.
- Handling customer queries face to face, over the phone or via correspondence.
- Marketing new financial products or services.
- Analyzing financial reports.
- Advising companies on how to effectively use their money to grow their business.
- Fresenting information clearly to customers, work colleagues and third parties.
- **EXECUTE:** Representing the bank within the local community.
- Verifying customer data to detect and identify financial fraud.
- Opening new bank accounts for individuals and also companies.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Banking competencies

- Thorough understanding of banking procedures.
- Knowledge of foreign currency.
- Profit & Loss management.
- Strategic planning.
- Presentation and sales skills.
- Knowledge of fund management.
- Good knowledge of finance and accounting.

Personal

- Dependable and truthful.
- Ability to keep calm under pressure.
- Self starter.
- Highly disciplined.
- Having the ability to work accurately.
- Attention to detail.
- Relationship management.
- Excellent negotiating skills.
- Comprehensive understanding of client confidentiality.
- Methodical and organized.
- Initiative and ingenuity.
- Ability to motivate subordinates.

KEY COMPETENCIES AND SKILLS

Customer satisfaction

Financial reporting

Business processes

Solution implementation

Portfolio management

Private banking

Commercial banking

Decision making

Asset and liability management

Online banking

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

- Master in Business Administration (Finance) from Madras University (Pursuing)
- Bachelor of Commerce from SRM College, Madras University, India, 2003-2006

OTHER CERTIFICATIONS

- AMFI
- IRDA
- NCFM

Other Detail

Computer Skills: Platforms MS DOS, MS Windows 98, 2000, Xp

Proficient and high levels of comfort with MS office

Word, Excel & Power Point.

Sports: Playing Cricket

Interests: Avid interest in listening music & Driving

Mobility: Willing to work anywhere in India and abroad

Languages: Fluent in English & Native Tamil

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth 25/10/1985

Gender Male

Married Married

Father B. Natarajan

Mother N Durga Rani (House wife) Spouse Name G Sujatha (House Wife)

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that all the particulars furnished above are true to the best of my knowledge.

REFERENCES - Available on request.

Place : Chennai Suresh.N